{"data":[{"question":"Tom _____ (dig) in the garden all afternoon and I _____ (help) him.","a":"has been digging\/ have been helping","b":"has been digging\/ has been helping","c":"have been digging\/ have been helping","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now(all afternoon)\n- Have\/has been + V-ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"6"},{"question":"He _____ (overwork). That is why he looks so tired.","a":"has been overworking","b":"have been overworking","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to emphasize someone keeps doing something in a period of time\n- He has been working....","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"7"},{"question":"The children _____ (look) forward to this holiday for months.","a":"has been looking","b":"have been looking","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now (for months)\n- The children (plural) + have been looking.....","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"7"},{"question":"That helicopter _____ (fly) round the house for the last hour; do you think it's taking photographs?","a":"has been flying","b":"have been flying","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now(for the last house)\n- The helicopter + has been + V-ing....","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"7"},{"question":"The car _____ (make) a very curious noise ever since it ran out of oil.","a":"has been making","b":"have been making","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now\n- The car has been making....","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"7"},{"question":"He _____ (study) Russian for two years and doesn't even know the alphabet yet.","a":"has been studying","b":"have been studying","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now(for two years)\n- He has been studying....","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"7"},{"question":"I _____ (make) cakes. That is why my hands are all covered with flour.","a":"has been making","b":"have been making","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous when there is a connection with now. The action in the past and has a result now\n- Have\/ has been + V-ing...","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"7"},{"question":"I'm on a diet. I _____ (eat) nothing but bananas for the last month.","a":"has been eating","b":"have been eating","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now (for the last month)\n- I have been eating....","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"7"},{"question":"We _____ (argue) about this for two hours now. Perhaps we should stop.","a":"has been arguing","b":"have been arguing","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now ( for two hours now)\n- We have been arguing.......","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"7"},{"question":"I _____ (ask) you to mend that window for six weeks. When are you going to do it?","a":"has been asking","b":"have been asking","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present perfect continuous to say how long for an activity that happened in the past, continues and still happening now (for six weeks)\n- I have been asking....","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"6","subcategorylv2":"2","type":"7"}]}